KAYLA ECKER

kaylaecker.com | kaylajayecker@gmail.com | 702-601-5807 | Seattle, WA

Profile

Full stack software engineer with quick ramp up on new technologies. Early career with years of transferable experience in incident response, teamwork, and communication. Why tech now? A passion for logic, puzzles, and building things with a flair for the creative.

Technical Skills

Languages used: Go, Ruby, Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java, HCL

Tools: Terraform (infrastructure as code), Linux, Ruby on Rails, Android Studio, Firebase, Trello, internal monitoring/alerting systems and graphing, version control management, and bug management

Best Practices: Incident Management, Object-Oriented Design, Test Driven Development, Agile Development

Past Projects

"Treebae" - https://treebae.herokuapp.com/ Project lead of a team of 4 with two weeks to create an e-commerce site; focus on MVC Tech Stack: Ruby, Ruby on Rails with a PostgreSQL database

"Playdate" - Android App Solo project completed in 3 weeks connecting interested users

Tech Stack: Java, Android Studio, Firebase

Cyber Security Hackathon - PNNL 2018 3rd place overall, capture the flag style

Education

Ada Developers Academy

Full-Stack Software Development Student in a highly selective (under 10%), intensive (fulltime, year long) software development training program dedicated to career transitioning University of Nevada, Las Vegas

B.A. Psychology

Focus: Research and Statistics Honors: Summa Cum Laude, Psi Chi

Technical Experience

Google

Software Engineer (Cloud Conversion SRE team) - Feb 2018 - Present

- Developing a Terraform library for automating alerting and monitoring policies for Stackdriver (hybrid monitoring for the Google Cloud), taken from conception to product launch, written in Golang
- * Creation and manipulation of virtual machines using Terraform and Google Cloud Platform, with particular consideration for scalability (using HCL)
- * Design and planning for project, including managing timelines. Creation and submission of design proposal, which analyzes objectives, requirements, scale, and alternatives considered. Receive feedback and make changes accordingly
- * Improve monitoring on metrics, graphs, alerts, and dashboards in Python/Java
- * Participate in Wheel of Misfortune, which is SRE role-playing training in response to pages, as part of on-call training

Past Work Experience

State of Nevada, Family Services Specialist 2 - 2013 - 2017

- * Project planning and documentation Worked with clients to create effective case plans and timelines. Beginning from the end goal point, created incremental goal markers to work towards intended conclusion
- * *Productivity* Managed an above average caseload, often meeting with up to 13 clients per day while the average was 6
- * Analysis and data collection Interviewed clients to receive pertinent information, analyzed collected data and made case decisions based on rules and regulations
- * Troubleshooting Functioned as unofficial IT for team, often needing to create work arounds for outdated software issues
- * Public Speaking and Communication Spoke to groups of 200+ in conference style, with use of visual aids and audience participation to elicit engagement
- * Teamwork Cross-departmental knowledge-sharing and effort coordination

Medicwest, Paramedic and Emergency Dispatcher - 2010 - 2013

- * Incident Management, Diagnostics Treatment of symptoms while doing fact finding to determine potential root causes of complaints
- * Emergency Management Remained calm and composed during crisis, deescalation and triage of emergency situations. Employed active listening and strong communication with patients, partners, and various agencies
- * Task Prioritization Determined priorities and task order based on need in a busy emergency system (population of nearly 2 million with a new response every 5 minutes, on average)
- Team Management Functioned as lead of crews of up to 30 teams, including with decision making and assuming responsibility for outcomes